A medal for honor. A search for justice. A battle for truth.
Courage Under Fire is a drama, thriller, mystery film directed by Edward Zwick.
A US Army officer, who made a "friendly fire" mistake that was
covered up, has been reassigned to a desk job.
He is tasked to investigate a female chopper commander's
worthiness to be awarded the Medal of Honor.
At first all seems in order.
But then he begins to notice inconsistencies between
the testimonies of the witnesses...
Lieutenant Colonel Nathaniel Serling, played by Denzel Washington.
Captain Karen Emma Walden, played by Meg Ryan.
Staff Sergeant John Monfriez, played by Lou Diamond Phillips.
Brigadier General Hershberg, played by Michael Moriarty.
Ilario, played by Matt Damon.
Bruno, played by Bronson Pinchot.
Courage Under Fire is a 1996 American war drama film directed by
Edward Zwick, and starring Denzel Washington and Meg Ryan.
It is the second collaboration between Washington and director Zwick.
The film was released in the United States on July 12, 1996, to
positive reviews and grossed $100 million worldwide.
It was also the first movie to be produced by Fox 2000 Pictures two
years after the company was established in 1994.
The film explores themes of gulf war, war veteran, politics, praise, pilot.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.